#### **GARY BORISKIN**

Resume of: Gary Boriskin

**Remote/Onsite: Remote** 

**Current Location: Chicago IL** 

Work Authorization: US Citizen

Availability to Interview: 1 Day notice

**Availability to Start: Immediately** 

Phone Number: 773-895-4535

**Previous FTE/Contractor: Contractor** 

Cleared for Rehire per CWM (Y/N): NA

Previous GuideWell/Florida Blue Hiring Manager: NA

### **Summary:**

GARY is Java Certified software engineer and has over 10 Years of Software Development experience. Involved in design, development and support of several applications and also used Continuous Integration tools-Jenkins. Worked on Spring Boot, AWS REST API deployed to Elastic Beanstalk, Spring MVC, and REST JSON API Web Services, IBM Data Stage ETL jobs to transfer data from Oracle RDB to Solr and Endeca search servers and Hybris Enterprise server, Excellent experience with Front end technologies like React, Handlebars, jQuery/Ajax, JSP. Gary is immediately available and has excellent communication skills.

## **Certifications:**

Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 7 Programmer **Technical Skills** 

Languages/Frameworks: Java, J2EE, Spring Boot, Spring/MVC, Struts, Python, Handlebars JS, Node/Express JS,

Angular, React, Python/Jython, Scala, jQuery/Ajax, C/C++, JSP, HTML/DHTML,

JavaScript, Perl, Unix shell scripting, PL/SQL, T-SQL.

Web Services: AWS, SOAP (XML), RESTFUL APIs (JSON).

**Development Tools:** RAD, Eclipse, IntelliJ, JDeveloper, Visual Studio, TOAD, SQL+, Dynatrace, Splunk.

**Databases:** Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Solr, Endeca, DB2, Microsoft Access.

**Application:** WebLogic 5-7, Tomcat 6-7, LifeRay 6-7, WebSphere 3.5-8.5, Silverstream 3.7.1-

3.7.2, E-Portal 2.2-2.3, Oracle Application Server 8i, 9i, Dynamo Application Server

4.2, Jboss 3.0, JRun, Microsoft IIS 4,5.

**Design Tools & Methodologies**: RUP/UML with Rational Rose, Star UML, Visio.

**Version control Tools:** GitHub, Bitbucket, Subversion, PVCS, IBM ClearCase.

Continues integration/: Jenkins, Ant, Gradle, and Maven. Jira, IBM ClearQuest, Service Now.

**Build/Tracking tools** 

**Testing APIs/Tools:** JUnit, Mockito/Spy, and Selenium IBM Data Stage, Informatica PowerCenter.

Search Servers: Solr, Endeca.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Grainger, Chicago, IL April 2019 – May 2020

**Software Engineer** 

- Software Technologies: AWS REST API, JAVA 1.8, Spring/MVC, JSP, Node/Express JS, React, Handlebars JS, Handlebars templates, jQuery/Ajax, JUnit/Mokito/Spy, HTML/DHTML, Restful Web Services, Hybris Enterprise server, Solr search server, Endeca search server, Oracle, MySQL.
- As a part of fully Agile Grainger Search team responsible for development and support of Grainger.com and mobile Grainger.com.
- Front end: React, Handlebars, ¡Query/Ajax, JSP.
- Back end: Spring Boot, AWS REST API deployed to Elastic Beanstalk, Spring MVC, REST JSON API Web Services, IBM Data Stage ETL jobs to transfer data from Oracle RDB to Solr and Endeca search servers and Hybris Enterprise server.

Blue Cross Blue Shield Association Sept 2006 – April 2019

Software Engineer/Tech Lead, Chicago IL

• Software Technologies: JAVA 1.4-8, J2EE, Python/Jython, JSP/JSF/STRUTS, Hibernate, Spring/MVC, jQuery/Ajax, JavaScript, HTML/DHTML, Web Services, T-SQL, PL/SQL.

- Member of Enterprise Information Technology team responsible for design, development and support of several applications for BCBSA. The applications provide means for data collection, data load, policy management; inter plans communication, reporting and data transfer.
- Responsibilities include requirements gathering, documentation, design, development and Leading off-site development and product verification resources.
- Application Servers: LifeRay 6-7, WebSphere 7-8.5, Adobe LiveCycle 4.
- RDBs: Oracle 10g, SQL Server 2014, My SQL.
- Build tools: ANT, Maven, Gradle.
- Continuous Integration tools: Jenkins.
- Code Repositories: GitHub, PVCS, Rational Clear Case.
- Operating systems: Windows, Unix Solaris, Linux.

# Acxiom, Chicago IL

Sept 2005 - Sept 2006

# **Software Engineer/Tech Lead**

- Market Knowledge Project. Responsible for design, development and project management of file arrival, job scheduling and process tracking application for Wolters Kluwer.
- Project utilized: JBOSS-4.0.3 application server J2EE, JSF, JSP, JSTL 1.0, Log4j, Oracle 9i, Hibernate 3.1, Spring 1.2.8, Ant 1.6, Data Stage ETL 7.5.
- Data Standardization Project. Responsible for design and development of Portal application for file layout and business rules
  management for Information Resources Inc. Project utilized: WebSphere 6.0, WebSphere Portal 5.1, RAD 6.0, Portal JSR 168 tags,
  J2EE 1.3, EJB 2.0, Web Services, Struts 1.1, JSP, JSTL 1.0, HTML, JavaScript, Hibernate 3.1, Oracle 9i, Ant 1.6, Unix C, ILog
  JRules 5.1, Data Stage ETL 7.5, Log4j, UML, Rational Clear Case as the source control. The applications were developed in
  Windows XP environment and deployed to Linux environment.

# ABN AMOR, Chicago IL Mar 2004 - Sept 2005

## **Software Engineer**

- CashProWeb project. Responsible for development and support of Web based and SWING GUI based applications for commercial customers enrollment, account management, data load, data migration and reporting. Project utilized: WebSphere 4.0, WebSphere 5.0, Novell Extend Director 5.0, Java 1.3-1.4, J2EE 1.3, EJB 2.0, JSP, SWING, Java Servlets, Struts 1.1, Oracle 8i, SQL Server 2000, WSAD 5.0, IBM MQSeries, Ant 1.6, PVCS, CVS, VSS, Solaris UNIX and Windows 2000.
- ABN Auto-enrollment project. Responsible for development and support of Web based Portal application for customer enrollment. Configuration and setting up Windows 2000, Linux and UNIX Solaris systems for installation of development and production environments. Development was done using Silver Stream 3.7.2 application server, IBM MQSeries, E-Portal 2.3 server, WOLFPACK 2.1.2, Java 1.3, E-Portal PID servlets, XML/XSL, FOP XML to PDF converter, HTML, RMI, CORBA, LDAP 4.0, Oracle 8i and SQL Server 7 database, E-Portal XML repository, Jbroker MQ JMS, Hibernate 2.0, Unix shell scripting, Ant 1.6, JBuilder X, use case diagrams, activity diagrams, sequence diagrams and class diagrams with Rational Rose 2000.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Chicago - Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science, Graduated